A Guide to the Sigrid L. Rupp Architectural Collection, 1950-2004
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- SERIES I. Personal Papers, 1954-2004.
  - SUBSERIES V: Student Work, 1950-1966.
    - Architecture 199, UC-Berkeley, 1964. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 103, 128, 289, UC-Berkley, Department of Architecture, Fall 1964-Spring 1965. (Box 64)
    - City and Regional Planning 100, UC-Berkeley, 1964. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 107, UC-Berkeley, 1965. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 128, UC-Berkeley, [The Alhambra: A Study], 1965. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 152, UC-Berkeley, [Project 1A and 1B - Light Study], 1965. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 1)
    - Major Design Thesis: A Remodeling of Seawall Warehouse for Synanon Inc., Spring 1966. (Box 126, Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 4)
    - Architecture and Religion in the Future City A Study: Presented at the 27th National Conference on Church Architecture, San Francisco, April 1966. (Box 64)
    - Architecture and Theology, notes and papers, undated. (Box 64)
    - German 100B, undated. (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous School Work, undated. (Box 64)
    - Photomontage, Palace of Fine Arts for the 1915 Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, CA, undated. (Box 150)
  - SUBSERIES IV: Photographs, 1973-2003.
    - Prints, 1982-2003.
      - Steve Rupp - miscellaneous trees, pulleys, gears, etc.. (Box 94)
      - Friends, Family, and Trips, circa 1982. (Box 94)
      - Masakazu and Izumi Kishikawa [Tokyo, Japan and visiting Rupp in the United States], 1996, 1998, and undated. (Box 94)
      - Unmarked [coastal scenes, mushrooms, plants] correspondes with negatives #9727, circa, 1999-2003. (Box 94)
      - Spring, 2000. (Box 94)
      - Fall/New Years Eve, 2001. (Box 94)
      - Almond Blossoms, Stanford "Goldsworthy," Spring 2002. (Box 94)
      - 60th Birthday celebration, 2003. (Box 94)
      - [photographs of watercolors]. (Box 94)
      - Unknown, descriptions on back. (Box 94)
      - Unknown, no descriptions on back. (Box 94)
      - Animals [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Buildings [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Clouds [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Flowers [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Hamilton Ave Gardens and house [Rupp's House] [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Miscellaneous Landscapes [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Paintings [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - People [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Rainbows [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Sunsets [category created by Rupp]. (Box 94)
      - Photographs of SLR, undated. (Box 94)
      - Panoramic Photographs [Mostly of the Baylands and surrounding area. Kept with watercolors--shows evidence of being used as reference visuals for watercolors]. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 1)
    - Negatives, 1981-2003.
      - Friends, Family, and Trips, circa 1982. (Box 101)
      - Family/Friends/Local Area, 1981-2003. (Box 115)
      - Pictures of SLR, undated. (Box 115)
      - Tasco, December 1981. (Box 106)
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-2003. (Box 116, Box 124)
      - Miscellaneous [sample subjects include nature scenes, flowers, gatherings of people, etc.]. (Box 124, Box 102)
    - Slides, 1973-1993.
      - Family and Friends, 1973-1982, and undated., Includes slides of SLR's graduation from UC-Berkeley (Box 110C)
      - Plants, SLR's home and garden, 1979; 1993 and undated. (Box 110D)
      - Miscellaneous., Includes slides of porsche parts, SLR owned artwork, miscellaneous churches, and unidentified slides (Box 110E)
      - Miscellaneous., Building; hotel room; old barn; Baylands [?] (Box 102)
    - Photoalbums, 1983-2003.
      - New Year's, 1983/1984. (Box 147)
      - 1986-1987. (Box 146)
      - 1988-1989. (Box 139)
      - 1990-1991. (Box 149)
      - 1992-1993. (Box 148)
      - 1994. (Box 137)
      - Garden, 1220 Hamilton Ave (Rupp's house). (Box 145)
      - 1996-1997. (Box 129)
      - 2003. (Box 143)
- SERIES II: Professional Papers, 1966-2003.
  The Professional Papers series consists of material relating to Rupp's participation in professional life including licenses, awards received, correspondence, and involvement in professional organizations (Rupp was president of California Women in Environmental Design from 1992 to 1993).
  - SUBSERIES I: General, 1966-2003.
    - Awards. (Box 152)
    - IAWA Donation- inventories, newsletter featuring SLR donation. (Box 89)
    - Boulgarides, Dr. James D., California State University, Los Angeles [study looking at women in architecture]. (Box 89)
    - Licenses/certifications/degrees for architecture, 1966-2003. (Box 89)
  - SUBSERIES II: Associations and Committees, 1985-2002.
    - AIA, Santa Clara Valley, 1997. (Box 89)
    - California Women in Environmental Design (CWED), 1992-1995.
      - 1993-1995. (Box 89)
      - Gabriella Judd Study, U.C. Berkeley, 1992. (Box 89)
      - Membership directory, 1994. (Box 89)
      - Newsletters from Rupp presidency, 1992-1993. (Box 89)
      - Newsletters from 1994 conference (SLR edition). (Box 89)
    - New Performance Gallery (American Inroads), 1985-1986. (Box 89)
    - Organization of Women Architects, retreat, 2002. (Box 142)
- SERIES III: Office Records, 1972-2002.
  The Office Records series consists of materials relating to the day to day operations of a private architectural practice including day planners (1982-2002), telephone logs (1976-1996), labor distribution (1983-1996), proposals and promotions (1976-1996), presentation materials, and publicity photographs.
  - SUBSERIES I: General, 1972-2002.
    - Accounts Receivable, 1997. (Box 69)
    - Advertising, 1993. (Box 69)
    - Articles - SLR, 1972; 1990-1992, undated. (Box 69)
    - Brochures, 1985-1986. (Box 69)
    - AIA Design Award, 1990. (Box 69)
    - Brochures, #8517 AT&T Seattle Metropolitan Park. (Box 69)
    - Brochure, Office Flyer. (Box 69)
    - Brochure Materials/Pages, pre-1990. (Box 69)
    - Brochures, SLR/International-Architects, Israel Office. (Box 69)
    - Clippings, #8018, Stanford University, Storey House. (Box 90)
    - Corporation Donations, 1986; 1989; 1990; 1993-1994. (Box 69)
    - Correspondence.
      - General, 1981; 1985-1995. (Box 8, Box 69)
      - Letters of Referral. (Box 69)
      - RE: Israel Office. (Box 69)
    - Day Planners, 1983-2002. (Box 70, Box 86)
    - Depreciation schedule, capital investments, 1978-1985. (Box 69)
    - Designer West, May 1985. (Box 69)
    - Elizabeth Rodenz, management consultant. (Box 69)
    - First computer purchase, word processor type, 1981. (Box 69)
    - Interiors, Second Annual Corporate America Design Awards featuring #8607 Raychem Corporation, May 1990. (Box 69)
    - Israel Furniture Week, (SLR/International), September 1983. (Box 69)
    - Labor Distribution, 1983-1996. (Box 89, Box 87, Box 88)
    - Margaret Spaulding/Marketing Consultant. (Box 69)
    - Miscellaneous Invoices, 1997. (Box 69)
    - Nepal, 1984. (Box 69)
    - Office content list, 1983-1984. (Box 69)
    - Overhead Expenses, 1977-1996. (Box 69)
    - P & L Statements [Profit and Loses], 1981-1990. (Box 77)
    - P & L Statements [Profit and Loses], 1991-2002]. (Box 69)
    - Photoalbum, SLR/Architects office photographs, 1981-1988. (Box 145)
    - [Portfolio of Projects from the 1970s]. (Box 69)
    - Russell Abraham Photography, billing and invoices, 1990-1996. (Box 77)
    - Service Contracts, 1977-1991.
      - Hewlett-Packard, service agreement, 1985. (Box 69)
      - Pacific Telephone, (blanket contract for professional services), 1977-1991. (Box 69)
      - Stanford University, service contract, 1978-1985. (Box 69)
      - Stanford University Medical Center, service contract, 1980-1987. (Box 69)
    - Slides, SLR/Architects projects. (Box 106)
    - SLR/Architects, 1976-1991.
      - Biography, 1979, 1987, and undated. (Box 69)
      - Employee Handbook - original. (Box 69)
      - Employee Handbook, 1991. (Box 69)
      - Miscellaneous Invitations/Christmas Cards. (Box 69, Box 152)
      - Offices, 1976-1987.
        - First office (for SLR), 1976-1977. (Box 69)
        - 320 Lytton (first office, SLR/Architects), lease information, [includes layout of how Rupp set-up the office], 1979-1987. (Box 69)
        - 320 Lytton, 1981-1987. (Box 69)
      - Tavi, [Israeli architecture magazine; has a profile of Digital Semiconductor Jerusalem, Architects: SLR International], 1983. (Box 69, Box 152)
      - Telephone logs, 1976-1996. (Box 87, Box 86)
  - SUBSERIES II: Computer Disks, 1978-1995, 2002. (Box 169, Box 170)
    The Computer Disks subseries contain various format disks, 8-inch; 5 ¼-inch; 3 ½-inch. They feature financial information, office records, and project files. 1978-1995, 2002.
    Access Restrictions
    The information on the computer disks have not been transferred to an accessible medium as of 2/2011.
  - SUBSERIES III: Photographs, Prints and Negatives 1974-1988.
    The photographs listed in this series are mainly presentation photographs that were grouped with other office records by Rupp. For additional project photographs see the Project Index.
    - #7606 Chantilly Restaurant (Box 90)
    - #7607 Baum Studio. (Box 90, Box 153)
    - #7701 Stanford University, Press Building (Box 90)
    - #7704 Residence, Palo Alto, CA (Box 90)
    - #7802 Residence (remodel), Los Altos, CA (Box 90)
    - #7809 United Airlines ticket office, Stanford Shopping Cente (Box 90)
    - #7813 AT&T Smokey Hills Radio Relay Repeater Station. (Box 90, Box 153)
    - #7815 PT&T. Dublin Phone Office (Box 90)
    - #7817 Eat Rite Nutrition Center (Box 90)
    - #7901 PT&T, Dublin phone store (Box 90)
    - #7916 Stanford University, RLG trailers (Box 90)
    - [#8003/17] PT&T Electric Switching Station (ESS), Richmond, CA (Box 90)
    - #8016 Ports International. (Box 90, Box 153)
    - #8018 Stanford University, Storey House. (Box 90, Box 153)
    - [#8019/20] Sweet Dreams, Stanford Shopping Center (Box 90)
    - [#8115] Blossoms Flower Shop, Hillsdale Mall, San Mateo, CA (Box 90)
    - #8202.01 Thoits, 625/631 Emerson, upgrade (Box 90)
    - #8211 Apple Caribbean, Sunnyvale, CA (Box 90)
    - #8304 Sugarman & Co., San Francisco, CA (Box 90)
    - [#8315] Malke-Sage Gallery, Cupertino, CA (Box 90)
    - #8403 Apple Computer Test Facility, Pescadero, CA (Box 90)
    - #8409 Raychem, 165 Jefferson Corporation Facility Offices, Menlo Park, CA (Box 90)
    - [8427/8525] Apple Computer, MIS facility (Box 90)
    - #8428 Apple Telecom Facility, Cupertino, CA (Box 91)
    - #8430 PT&T, 910 Marshall Street, Redwood City, CA (Box 91)
    - #8517 AT&T Seattle, Metropolitan Park (Box 91)
    - #8511 AT&T, OSPS, North Hollywood, CA (Box 91)
    - #8605 AT&T, SSC & ATTIS, Sacramento, CA (Box 91)
    - #8607 Raychem, 2415 Bay Road, Woodside, CA, Furniture and art (Box 91)
    - #8712 Grid Systems, offices and assembly plant, Fremont, CA (Box 91)
    - #8713 SLR/Architects, Office, 1935 University (Box 91)
    - #8720 Claris, 440 Clyde Ave, Mountain View, CA (Box 91)
    - #8724 Apple, Bubb Road, Research Facility (Box 91)
    - #8721.05 Caesar Chavez (Ravenwood MS), Science Classroom (Box 91)
    - #8805 Brownstein/Bessemer (Box 153)
    - #8806 Residence, Los Altos, CA (Box 91)
    - #8913 Jack and Cohen Office (Box 91)
    - #8915 Residence, Palo Alto, CA (Box 91)
    - #8922 Residence, West Harwich Port, MA (Box 91)
    - [9001?] and 9310 Raychem, Building ABC (Box 91)
    - #9008 Stanford University, Building 370, Quad, Seismic Renovation (Box 91)
    - #9011 Residence, Hillsborough, CA (Box 91)
    - #9101 Rancho Murieta Water Treatment, Rancho Murieta,CA (Box 91)
    - #9309.01 Raychem, Commons Cafe and Conference Rooms (Box 91)
    - #9313 Cafe & Co. of Carmel, Crossroads Shopping Center, Carmel, CA (Box 91)
    - Apple Computer, undated. (Box 153)
    - AT&T Communications Billing Center. (Box 153)
    - Biebrach Swim Pool (Box 91)
    - Brentwood School, Ravenswood School District (Box 91)
    - Israel, Miscellaneous Projects (Box 91)
    - Opera Plaza Drycleaners (Box 91)
    - Patricia Webster School for Dance Arts (Box 91)
    - Raychem Corporation, undated. (Box 153)
    - Miscellaneous residence. (Box 153)
    - Various Projects [includes prints and negatives]. (Box 125, Box 91)
  - SUBSERIES IV: Portfolios,., 1978-1995
    The Portfolios series is comprised of reduced reproductions of drawings that Rupp organized by year or in a few cases by project ns2:title (Storey House and Raychem Corporation ABC). Not all project numbers have a set of reduced drawings see the Project Index for listings.
  - SUBSERIES V: Proposals/Promotions, 1976-1996.
    - Promotions/Proposals, 1981-1993, 1996. (Box 89)
    - Past Proposals, 1993-1996.
      - Proposal - Office of the State Architect, State of California, Proposal for Consultant Manager, 1976. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - modifications to buildings 500, 516, 518, and 520, Stanford University Mechanical Engineering, January 30, 1978. (Box 90)
      - Proposals - A.T.&T Longlines, February 28, 1981. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Stanford University Medical Center Edwards Renovation Department of Surgery, August 2, 1982. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Refurbishing of Student Lounges, San Jose State University, 1982. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Design Approach Telecommunication Building, Stanford University, 1983. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - 300 Workstation, Western Division Naval FAC Engineering Command, June 14, 1985. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Qualification Submittal, Postal Facility for Morgan Hill, California, (a joint venture with Jensen, Johnson, and SLR/Architects), October 1985. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Expansion of the Price Waterhouse Technology Centre, January 7, 1987. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Qualifications Statement, Northern Regional Library Facility, Step 2, March17, 1987. (Box 90)
      - Proposals - Renovations and Refurbishing of the Altenheim, July 18, 1990. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Statement of Qualifications, University of California, Davis, Architect/Engineer/and other design professionals, 1991. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - U.C. Berkeley, August 1993. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Building 01-250 Seismic Upgrade Stanford University, Project no. 6120, August 29, 1996. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Renovation and Remodeling of 625/631 Emerson Street. (Box 90)
      - Promotion - East Palo Alto "Can Do" Project Mid-Peninsula Housing Coalition. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - For the Green Library Stack Seismic Bracing. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - A Statement of Qualification to the City Milpitas, Neighborhood Center Building Milpitas, California, Building Renovation Program. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Statement of Qualifications, Raychem R&D Center Renovation and Reconstruction. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Applied Physics Annex, Stanford University. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - A Statement of Qualifications for the Reconstruction of Storey House, Stanford University. (Box 90)
      - Proposal - Unitrans Maintenance Facility Qualification Statement. (Box 90)
  - SUBSERIES VI: Presentation Materials, 1976-1995.
    - #7607 Baum studio. (Box 90)
    - #7813 AT&T Longlines Relay Station. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2, Box 90)
    - #8211 Apple Caribbean, Sunnyvale, CA. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)
    - #8403 Apple Radio Frequency Test Facility. (Oversize Framed profile, Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)
    - #8713 SLR/Architects--1935 University. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)
    - #8719, Maui Sands, Maui Hawaii, 1987. (Box 90)
    - #8824 Raychem Corporation, ABC Building. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)
    - #9512 Nugent Square. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)
    - Raychem Corporation. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)
    - University Circle, Design Studies, July 6, 1990. (Box 90, Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)
- SERIES IV: Project Records, 1976-2003.
  The Project Records series has been arranged into a Project Index which is a way to organize the various formats of architectural records from the same project. The index is arranged chronologically by project number and contains information, where available, about the location, date, project type, architect, collaborators, photographers, and formats for each project in the collection.
  A sampling of clients that can be found in the Project Index include: Apple Computer, Sun Microsystems, Tandem, Amdahl, Claris, Raychem, and IBM, AT&T, Pac Bell, United Airlines, Pan Am, Stanford University and Hospital, San Jose State University, and numerous individual residences. Some general files related to project records are listed below.
  - Job Data Sheets, #8403-#8520. (Box 57)
  - Master Specifications. (Box 57)
  - Morgue Files,.
    The "morgue" files contains mostly duplicates of materials held in the project files. They are filed chronologically.
    - 1976 [includes General correspondence]. (Box 57)
    - Fourth Quarter, 1980-June 1982. (Box 78)
    - July 1982-December 1983. (Box 79)
    - January 1984-October 1985. (Box 80)
    - November 1985-December 1986. (Box 81)
    - January 1987-August 1988. (Box 82)
    - September 1988-September 1990. (Box 83)
    - October 1990-June 1993. (Box 84)
    - July 1993-December 1996. (Box 85)
    - 1997. (Box 62)
    - 1999. (Box 62)
  - Project Book, 1978-1989. (Box 57)
  - Project Book, 1990-current [1996]. (Box 57)
- SERIES V: Art and Artifacts.
  - Artwork, mostly watercolors. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 1)
  - Portraits by SLR: 1)self-portrait 2)unidentified male. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 1)
  - Sketchbook, color study. (Oversize Map-case 14/Drawer 2)